[Music]
Hello
friends welcome back to our
Channel I am your tasa instructor and my
name is karesh thank you for connecting
with
us hope you are doing well
let's start our today's session through
this video I will guide you about how to
register in tricentis TSA support portal
using the business email activation of
trial license for 60 days downloading
the latest TSA setup after activation of
license and steps to install the
tool also we will understand how to
configure the trial
license all right let's starts with the
user registration in tricentis support
portal Tusa is not an open-source tool
so we can't directly download the
software from
internet first we need to perform user
registration and activate the trial
license for 60 days after that we will
be able to download the Tusa from
support
portal let's have a look on
this to open to the trient support
portal search the keyword TSA download
and click on the first option in the
Google search or we can directly enter
the address https colon sl/ support.
trendy.com commmunity in browser address
[Music]
bar after entering into support portal
we need to click on the register button
for the user reg first we need to enter
the details in login data section
including email and password for
login the support portal only allow your
business or professional email for the
[Music]
registration the general emails such as
Google Yahoo are not
[Music]
accepted the user registration is
one-time activity for any particular
users now user needs to enter the
personal details such as name phone
number Time Zone Etc
next company data has to be provided
which will be verified later by the
tricenter support team during the trial
license
[Music]
activation accept the privacy policy and
Pro proceed with user
registration on success verification
mail will be sent to registered
[Music]
email depending on the network speed it
may take sometimes to receive the
verification mail which contains the
verify link here we need to click on
verify me now link
[Music]
after successfully verification a
success popup message will be
displayed now the user registration
process has been completed and we can
proceed to activate trial
license after the user registration 60
days trial license activation is
required to download the tool from
support portal to activate the license
first user need to be logged in using
the loging credential which is created
during the user registration
[Music]
now open the link
https support. trends.com community/
trining licore request. to raise the
request here two options are available
as preferred license type in in training
license request page we will select
Cloud license type to configure the Tusa
using the registered credential to
connect trial license later the other
option on premise is used to configure
the license in a standalone system after
submitting license request and success
popup will appear and Confirmation mail
will be
received now we are ready to download
the Tusa tool here we need to click on
downloads tab new page will appears with
the list of products which are available
for download by clicking any of the Tusa
product link we can initiate the
downloads the time for download will be
depends on the network speed and the
size of
[Music]
product we will skip this step and
continue with
installation all right let us start the
installation once the download is
completed the downloaded zip file will
be available in the download
location now extract the zip
file it may takes for a few seconds to
complete the unzip process
[Music]
now open the extracted folder
now doubleclick on the setup file to
open the setup
wizard from this screen accept the
license terms and click on continue to
initiate the
installation click next to install the
prerequisites components and move to
type selection
screen we will select option Tusa
commander and proceed to the screen for
selection of different paths if required
the paths can be changed we keep the
default configuration and proceed next
from the diagnostic screen unchecking
the check box as we don't want to send
any usage
statistics click on
next keeping the vision AI engine
setting as it is move to the next review
screen the list of features which are
going to install are listed here the
features can be changed from the review
screen now click on install button to to
start the
installation the installation will take
a couple of minutes the features wise
installation status can be viewed from
here the green tick will be displayed
for successful installation against each
of the feature name we need to wait to
complete the installation
[Music]
after the successfully installation the
Finish button will be appears click
finish to complete and exit from
installation
wizard now we are going to learn how to
configure the trial license we will
configure the license using the Tusa
license Configuration
utility same can be done through the
Tusa Commander as well as the trial
license is already activated we need to
click on
[Music]
connect we need to select connect to CL
Cloud hosted license server and proceed
as the cloud option had been opted
during trial license
activation here the activated tosa
license credential there'll be the same
login details which was created during
the
registration enter the details and click
on okay button now TSA is trying to
validate the credential which was used
to connect the cloud
license this validation process will
take few seconds depends on the network
speed this is an onetime
activity from the next time the license
server will be automatically connected
while launching the
[Music]
Tusa success message will be displayed
and the Li server has been connected now
close the Tusa license Configuration
utility open the Tusa Commander to check
that entire setup is working as expected
while launching Tusa Commander will
automatically validate and connect to
the cloud license server it will take
few seconds
[Music]
this is the initial screen of Tusa
Commander with active
license the license can also be
configured from the commander as well
through the license
[Music]
tab thanks for watching this video
that's all about Tusa setup and
configuration topic we will learn more
about Tusa workspace Creation in next
TSA tutorial
please visit our website lamb geeks.com
for more articles on technology
engineering mathematics and various
other domain you can check our other
website as
well we have features like YouTube
trends Twitter
Trends scientific calculator and many
more other
[Music]
tools if you like our video please like
comment and share if you have any
questions please comment and we will
resolve your query